A Guide to the George Green Shackelford Papers 1955-1985
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
George Green Shackelford Papers 1955-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3525-aq
This collection consists of ca. 347 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the Library on July 18, 1986, by George Green Shackelford of Blacksburg, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
These personal papers of George Green Shackelford, 1955-1985, are mainly concerned with the Monticello Association, particularly the publication of the Collected Papers of the Monticello Association, Volumes I and II, for which Shackelford served as editor. There are also letters from George Scott Shackelford, Jr., and Evelyn Shackelford and their family, 1955-1978, which convey personal and family matters, as well as the Shenandoah Club and the restoration of the "Smithfield Plantation," Montgomery County, Va.
The correspondence chiefly concerns the commemorative volume, The Collected Papers of the Monticello Association, Volume I, (Princeton University Press, 1965), celebrating the 50th anniversary of the Association. Aspects involved in the preparation of the volume include writing sketches, editing chapters, sales, distribution of a brochure prior to publication, and the printing of the book. Correspondents include members of the Monticello Association and other interested perosns such as Julian P. Boyd, George H. Esser, Jr., Randolph Bolling Hubard, Archer Jones, Robert H. Kean, and Gerald Morgan, Jr., as well as associates of the Princeton University Press.
Papers of the Monticello Association contain minutes of meetings, progress reports, manuscripts, and related material concerning the publication of the commemorative volume, and later, Volume II of the Collected Papers of the Monticello Association(University of Virginia, 1984). Correspondents in the "Collected Papers..." folders include Olivia Taylor, John H. Randolph, Edward "Pete" Churchill, Sidney M. Ruffin, Robert H. Kean, George H. Esser, and Stuart E. Brown, Jr.; and correspondents found in the "Monticello Association Correspondence..." folders include Bernard P. Chamberlain, Edgar F. Shannon, Thomas Page Nelson, Randolph Bolling Hubard, Harold J. Coolidge, and Mary Walker Randolph. The collection also contains a plat and a topographical map of the graveyard property at Monticello, 1975.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence: A-J 1958-1969 (Box 1)
    13 items
  - Correspondence: K-N 1959-1966 (Box 1)
    9 items
  - Correspondence: Gerald Morgan, Jr. 1959-1965 (Box 1)
    17 items
  - Correspondence: Princeton University Press 1959-1966 (Box 1)
    22 items
  - Correspondence: George Scott Shackelford, Jr. and Evelyn Shackelford 1955-1978 (Box 1)
    50 items
- Topical
  - Annual Meeting Minutes and Reports of the Monticello Association 1957-1985 (Box 1)
    30 items
  - Collected Papers of the Monticello Association- Miscellaneous 1978-1981 (Box 1)
    33 items
  - Collected Papers of the Monticello Association- Miscellaneous 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    37 items
  - Collected Papers of the Monticello Association- Miscellaneous 1984-1985, n.d. (Box 1)
    52 items
  - Mercier Four Seasons Paintings owned by Mrs. John S. Rixey 1973 (Box 2)
    6 items
  - Monticello Association Correspondence and Papers 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Monticello Association Correspondence and Papers 1970-1975 (Box 2)
    42 items
  - Graveyard Property Located at Monticello 1974-1975 (Box 2)